[creature squawking]
[creatures squawking]
[creatures continue squawking]
[doo-wop song playing]
Over the mountain
Across the sea
There's a girl
She's waiting for me
[yawning]
[moans]
Cross over the river
Beyond every cloud
She's passed the wind
[rumbling]
That's blowing loud
[moans]
Over the mountain
A girl waits for me
Tell all the sands
[sniffing]
And every blade of grass
Mm.
Please tell the wind to let my love pass
[growling softly]
Over the mountain
A girl waits for me
[device whirring]
[heavy footsteps thudding]
[faint, muffled footsteps]
[muffled grunting]
[roars]
[roaring loudly]
[distant explosion]
[soft explosion]
[alarm blares]
[automated voice on speaker]
Alert, biodome breach.
Dr. Andrews, did you see that?
The habitat's not gonna
hold much longer.
We need to start thinking
about off-site solutions.
The island is the one thing
that's kept him isolated.
If he leaves,
Godzilla will come for him.
There can't be two alpha Titans.
The whole theory of an ancient rivalry
stems from Iwi mythology.
He's gotten too big over time.
This environment
won't sustain much longer.
It's too unstable.
- Hey.
- [in sign language]
[in sign language]
[sighs]
Off-site would be a death sentence.
You don't think the King
could take care of himself?
There has to be another way.
[man 1 ] Finding the origin
of these creatures
is essential to mankind's survival.
[man 2] The interior of the Earth
is made up of vast caverns
and air pockets,
joined by natural avenues.
[man 3] The admiral
begins his expedition,
searching for an entrance
to a hidden world.
[man 4] The purpose is the discovery
and the release to the world
of the unknown treasures of Antarctica
in the interests of all mankind.
[man 5] Members of the lost
party were never seen again.
Still no word
on what may have happened.
[man 6] There's an ecosystem out there,
the likes of which we can't imagine.
And the place to find it is this island.
[growling]
[man] Hello, loyal listeners.
Welcome to TTP, Titan Truth Podcast.
Episode number 245.
Today is the day.
Maybe the last podcast I ever record.
And look, I know I said that last week
and maybe the week before
and a few other times.
But, look, this is the point.
After five years of deep cover
at Apex Cybernetics,
I'm finally taking my shot.
Something bad is going on here.
I don't know what it is,
but I'm about to walk in
and download hard evidence
and expose a vast corporate conspiracy.
Yeah, you can call me a whistleblower,
but I ain't just whistling.
I mean, this is more than a leak.
It's a flood.
And believe me, this flood
is gonna wash away all of Apex's lies.
You can believe that.
[automated voice on speaker]
Welcome to Apex Cybernetics.
No unauthorized persons allowed
beyond this point.
[man on TV] When we started
Apex Cybernetics,
we dreamt of new ways to push past
the limits of human potential.
Robotics, the human mind,
artificial intelligence.
Who knows what brave new future
we'll dream of next?
I'm Walter Simmons,
and it is my privilege to lead Apex
into humanity's bold new era.
We're not going anywhere.
And neither are you.
[man] There you are, baby.
[indistinct chatter on radio]
No, don't eat that!
It's incredibly unhealthy.
It's just all the GMOs.
Growing a second head could be useful.
You have to let me know.
Because me, myself?
I can barely handle
the one I got. [chuckles]
Bernie, you're not
supposed to be in here.
You ever wonder
what we're really doing here?
I mean, really doing here.
Why are you here?
This isn't Engineering.
Because, you know, I had to wait
because they're rendering
these new specs,
which is gonna take over, uh...
That's calculator mode.
...over one hour, maybe even more.
So my foreman told me
to just take a walk
- and make some new friends.
- Oh.
Oh! Now that we're new friends,
I can share something with you, right?
I know it's in here somewhere.
This is hand sanitizer that I made
from my own garden.
It's really amazing.
Don't know if I used that or not.
[exclaims]
Yes. This. Check this out.
That right there
is radio mesh networking
with a voice-record subprocessor.
- Guess from where. Come on.
- I don't care.
A toaster! [chuckles]
It's from a toaster. Look at this thing.
I have to go to the bathroom.
Is it one or two? 'Cause if it's two,
it's probably from these apples.
Hey, you wanna use the hand sanitizer
that I made?
I'm good.
Okay, I'll just stay here.
[softly] Okay. Yeah.
Ah, let's see.
Whoo.
Screen.
What are they shipping to Hong Kong?
What's Sublevel 33?
What the...?
- [alarm blares]
- [gasps]
[automated voice on PA]
Evacuation, Titan alert.
[man on PA] This is not a drill.
All Apex employees, please proceed...
That is my cue. That's my cue.
[man on PA] This is not a drill.
[indistinct shouting]
[roars]
Proceed to the fallout shelter
in a single-file line. Let's go!
[Bernie] They used cyanide capsules
instead of fallout shelters
to keep the secrets in,
but, you know,
that's neither here nor there,
so don't listen to me.
[guard] Level two personnel, this way!
Let's go, let's go!
Yeah, that way.
It's time!
We need to go now!
[indistinct shouting]
[people screaming]
[automated voice] Evacuate.
[panting] One level at a time, okay.
- No.
- Hey, you!
- Where's your clearance tag?
- You know what?
The fact that you're talking about
clearance tags right now
in a time of crisis
is incredibly unprofessional.
We should be talking about evacuation.
- [cocks gun]
- Yo! Okay!
- [rumbling]
- [Bernie yelps]
- [high-pitched screech]
- [screams]
[Bernie coughing]
[grunts] Oh, my God.
[mechanical warbling and clanking]
Oh, no. What the hell is that?
[mechanical clanking]
[people screaming]
[roaring]
[news theme music plays]
[announcer] This is CNN breaking news.
[anchor] The United States
Navy's Fourth Fleet is deployed
off the southeastern
seaboard of the U.S.
after last night's
sudden Godzilla attack.
A time of relative peace shattered
when the massive Titan,
once thought to be a hero to humanity,
made landfall in Pensacola, Florida.
While the damage was largely contained
to the U.S. headquarters
of Apex Cybernetics,
governments around the world
aren't taking any chances
after the first substantiated
Titan sighting in over three years.
CEO Walter Simmons had this to say.
It's about working together
to ensure a safer world.
Godzilla's a threat to humanity,
and Apex has a plan to deal with it,
- once and for all.
- [school bell rings]
[woman on PA] Students and faculty,
please be advised
a mandatory assembly will be held
at 2:00 p.m. this afternoon.
Guidance counselors will also be holding
additional office hours all this week
for individual and group sessions.
[Bernie on speaker] Welcome back,
loyal listeners,
to Titan Truth Podcast, episode 246.
Oh, my God. I was there.
Godzilla's Apex attack.
I saw it go down!
You think it's a coincidence
that he reappears
and just so happens to destroy
that specific facility?
Ha-ha, no, no, no, no.
No such thing as coincidence.
[Madison] Dad, I'm telling you,
there's something provoking him
that we're not seeing here.
Why else would Godzilla
flash an intimidation display
if there wasn't another Titan around?
That podcast is filling your head
with garbage.
- You should be in school.
- I am just trying to help.
I don't want you to help.
I want you to stay safe.
We needed a plan to keep peace
with these things,
and the best one we had
just went down in flames.
I don't have any more.
And the last thing that I need
is to be worrying about you.
Godzilla saved us.
You were there with Mom. You saw it.
How could you doubt him?
- There has to be a pattern.
- There doesn't.
- A reason why he was provoked.
- There isn't.
How do you know that?
Because creatures,
like people, can change.
And right now, Godzilla's out there
and he's hurting people,
and we don't know why.
So cut your pop some slack, would ya?
See you at home, Dad.
[Bernie] You wanna know my theory?
I mean, of course you do.
That's why you're here.
Come on, it's all about
patterns and variables.
Oh, wait, stick with me.
I'm gonna take you back
to sixth grade with this, okay?
Godzilla attacks when provoked,
that's the pattern.
Pensacola is the only coastal Apex hub
with an advanced robotics lab.
That's the variable.
And add them up and your answer is
that Apex
is at the heart of the problem.
- [faint beep]
- [door closes]
Can I help you?
If you want an appointment,
my office hours are nine to five.
- [Walter] Please, Dr. Lind.
- What the f...
Guys like you and me,
we don't do normal hours, do we?
I've been fixated on Hollow Earth
for as long as you have.
Your theory that it's the birthplace
of all Titans is fascinating.
Your book was very impressive.
Oh, yeah?
Well, I got about 30 unsold boxes
in my apartment if you want some.
[chuckles]
Walt Simmons.
I know who you are, sir. It's an honor.
No, the honor is mine.
As is the urgency.
Godzilla has never attacked us
unprovoked before.
These are dangerous times, Dr. Lind.
Allow me to introduce
our Apex chief technology officer,
Mr. Ren Serizawa.
He has an interesting thing to show you.
[beeps]
Magnetic imaging
from one of our new satellites.
You know what this is, right?
[Nathan] Hollow Earth.
[Walter] An ecosystem
as vast as any ocean,
right beneath our feet.
This energy signal is enormous.
And almost identical
to readings from Gojira.
[Walter] As our sun
fuels the planet's surface,
this energy sustains the Hollow Earth,
enabling life as powerful
as our aggressive Titan friend.
If we can harness this life force,
we'll have a weapon
that can compete with Godzilla.
I need your help to find it.
[chuckling]
I don't know if I'm the right guy
for the job.
Did you read the reviews?
"A sci-fi quack
trading in fringe physics."
Look where they put my office.
I'm in the basement
right across from flute class.
Besides, I'm not with Monarch anymore.
And Hollow Earth entry is impossible.
We tried.
I'm sorry about your brother.
He was a true pioneer.
Thanks.
[sniffles, clears throat]
See, all of our forward scans
suggest a habitable environment
down there.
So, what really went wrong
on your brother's mission?
When they tried to enter,
they hit a gravitational inversion.
A whole planet's worth of gravity
reversed in a split second.
They were crushed in an instant.
What if I told you that we, at Apex,
have created a phenomenal craft
which could sustain such an inversion?
The Hollow Earth Aerial Vehicle.
HEAV.
We can make the journey
to Hollow Earth possible, Dr. Lind.
But we need you to lead the mission.
Help me.
Help everyone.
Finding this needle in a haystack
is our best shot against Godzilla.
Well, I, uh, might have an idea.
But it's crazy.
I love crazy ideas. They made me rich.
[Nathan] Are you guys familiar
with genetic memory?
It's a theory that all Titans
share a common impulse
to return to their evolutionary source.
Like spawning salmon.
Exactly. Or a... Or a homing pigeon.
So if this is the Titans' home
and this life force sustains them...
A Titan could show you the way.
[Nathan] Yeah.
With a little help of an old colleague.
[grunts softly]
[Ilene] Ugh, where is it?
[receptionist] Dr. Andrews,
you have a visitor
waiting for you at security.
[in sign language]
[sighs] Okay.
[chuckles softly]
[thunder rumbles]
[Ilene] A power source in Hollow Earth?
This sounds nuts, Nathan, even for you.
[Nathan] It's there!
We just need Kong to bring us to it!
[Ilene] The second you take Kong
out of containment,
Godzilla's gonna come for him.
[Nathan] You said you can't
keep him here forever.
No. Our meddling has already
wreaked havoc on Kong's habitat.
No way am I letting you drag him
halfway across the world
to use him as a weapon.
[Nathan] No, not as a weapon.
As an ally.
To protect us, lead the way down there.
What even makes you think
that he'll go in?
You always believed that Skull Island
was like Hollow Earth
come to the surface, right?
And that's where Kong's ancestors
came from.
Mm-hmm.
Through the entrance in Antarctica,
we could help him find a new home.
And he could save ours.
Hers.
That power source may be our only hope.
We gotta stop Godzilla.
This is our only chance.
We have to take it.
[creatures chittering]
[electrical crackling and humming]
[sighs]
- Okay.
- Yes!
But when it comes to Kong,
what I say goes.
You name the terms. Thank you.
Sorry. Thank you.
You won't regret this.
- Mm, I already regret this.
- [thudding]
- [sighs]
- [in sign language]
[Ilene sighs]
[exhales heavily] Come on.
[country song playing]
If you could see me now
The one who said that he'd rather roam
[breathing heavily]
The one who said he'd rather be alone
If you could only see me now
I've been too long in the wind
Too long in the rain
[indistinct radio chatter]
Taking any comfort that I can
Looking back and longing for
The freedom of my chains...
[door thuds, buzzer sounds]
Whoo! Jeez,
I can smell him from up here.
Well, he can smell you, too.
[Kong moaning]
Still not a fan, huh?
[in sign language]
What's she saying?
Just an Iwi expression.
It means that you're very brave.
- Yeah?
- [Ilene] Mm-hmm.
[Nathan] Hey, use a light touch
on the sedatives.
He's our escort.
We can't have him comatose
when we reach Hollow Earth.
What if Kong doesn't go willingly?
- What do you do then?
- [PA chimes]
[woman on PA] Dr. Lind, please report
to the forward deck. Dr. Lind.
Excuse me.
- New arrivals.
- [in sign language]
- [metal creaks]
- [Kong grunting]
[growls softly]
Welcome.
Wow. Who's the idiot
who came up with this idea?
- Ha-ha.
- I'm Maia Simmons.
My father sent me.
I run point for Apex.
Nathan Lind, mission chief.
[Kong growls]
Yeah, don't worry.
I'm just here to babysit.
- [Kong growls]
- [metal clangs]
The Hollow Earth Aerial Vehicles are
on their way to Antarctica as we speak.
I know you people
think you're cutting-edge,
but these prototypes we're loaning you
will make what you've been flying
look like used Miatas.
I love Miatas.
Forget about the price tag,
which is obscene, of course.
The antigravity engines alone produce
enough charge
to light up Vegas for a week.
Feel free to be impressed.
Wow.
[thunder crashes]
[moaning]
[Nathan] All right, we'll be
at the Antarctica entry in 48 hours.
This path will get us into Hollow Earth.
Once we're inside,
Kong should lead us to the power source.
Now, the gravitational inversion
will be quite intense.
Our best guess is that on entry,
it'll feel like bungee jumping...
with the cord tied
to your lower intestine.
But if your helicopters
are as good as you say...
HEAVs.
If your HEAVs are as good
as you say they are,
I believe we can do this.
[Maia] They'll do the job.
You just gotta do yours.
Excellent.
[Wilcox] Dr. Andrews.
We've avoided all of Godzilla's
known territorial waters
according to your guidelines.
Good.
Do I need to be concerned?
Yes. They do have a way
of sensing threats.
And we believe that they had
an ancient rivalry.
The myths say that their ancestors
fought each other in a great war.
So if they meet again,
who bows to who, is that it?
[scoffs]
No, I spent ten years
on that island studying him.
I know this for sure.
Kong bows to no one.
[faint, muffled moaning]
[muffled pulsing]
[pulsing quickening]
[rain pattering]
[loud thud]
Is she supposed to be out there?
- [thudding continues]
- [metallic whining]
[roars]
[faint, muffled roaring]
[faint, muffled grunting]
[Kong grunts softly]
[Kong moaning]
Jia, come on. Come on.
[in sign language]
[huffs]
[moaning]
[grunting softly]
[groaning]
Did the monkey just talk?
[Bernie on speaker]
Okay, class, listen up.
In the midst of Godzilla's attack
on Apex Pensacola,
I found some crazy tech
with no official classification.
What I saw doesn't match
any of the engineering specs
I've ever seen.
So what are they working on
in such blackout secrecy, hmm?
This could be the thread
that finally unravels
the Apex sweater of conspiracy.
You better believe
I'm gonna keep tugging.
For now, I'm secure.
Anonymous and hiding in plain sight
as I continue my mission.
["Breaking The Law"
blaring on van speaker]
Breaking the law
[music stops]
To be clear, my brother
can never know we took his van.
Josh, to be clear,
even if we got into an accident,
I don't think he could tell.
No, no, my brother would never
let you drive either.
My mission, my wheel.
I just don't think it's a good idea,
looking for some secret weirdo
off the Internet.
I mean, we just had
an assembly about this.
He's not a weirdo.
He's a covert investigator.
And he's the only one
looking for the truth
about Godzilla and Apex.
So let him look.
Why do we have to help him?
[sighs] Because...
If we don't, nobody else will.
Are you coming or not?
Obviously I'm coming.
[van door rattles]
It's stuck.
- [engine revs]
- Wait, wait, wait, wait!
[Bernie on speaker] Mind control.
Read up on it, sheep.
Psionic link technology is a reality.
That's right.
One brain controlling another.
Oh, man.
[Bernie] Imagine that on a global scale
and Apex is invincible.
We've been listening
to this weirdo for hours.
- [Madison] Whoa, whoa, whoa!
- [tires screech]
Whoa! Knock it off!
Wait, this is the part
I was telling you about.
[Bernie] ...need special UV
to even know you've been marked!
One or two gallons won't cut it.
I need my bleach in bulk!
Because spy dust is real, people!
I mean, come on,
invisible to the naked eye...
- [turns off stereo]
- That's how we find him.
- The bleach.
- Bleach?
He consumes a ton of bleach.
He drinks bleach?
Showers with it.
Oh! Yeah, I shower with bleach.
No, what?
Prevention against
organic tracking technology.
See? Tradecraft.
Would've made more sense
if he just drank it.
[Madison] Come on, just one more place.
Madison, this is getting old.
Hey, you sell bleach?
Is this another one of those
Internet challenge things?
When I sold those kids
those detergent pods,
I didn't know they were gonna eat them.
I'm still dealing
with the lawsuits from that.
Look, we're looking for a guy
who works for Apex Cybernetics.
Buys a lot of bleach. Like every night.
He's probably paranoid,
high-strung, doesn't like daylight.
You know, has a lot of crumbs
in his beard, if he has a beard.
Okay, look, you kids want some candy?
Because I can help you with candy.
Look at me in the eye. Okay?
I need information.
Yeah, we want lots of candy.
What are you doing?
You think...?
Oh, you mean Bernie.
Yeah, I know that guy.
He buys, like, a ton of bleach.
I know where he is, too.
If you buy a live fish,
I'll give you his address.
[banging on door]
[Madison] Bernie?
[Bernie] Mister...
[clears throat] Mis...
- [thud]
- [Bernie groans]
[in deep voice] Mister Bernie not home.
- Yep, that was definitely Mister Bernie.
- Yeah. Um...
Hi! Hi. Listen, we wanna talk
about Apex and Godzilla.
[Bernie] No. No. No.
I... I got your faces.
I contact authorities. Yes.
[Josh] For knocking on a door?
[Bernie chuckles] No. No.
Bernie, you don't trust the authorities.
My name is Madison Russell.
My father works for Monarch
and my mother was...
Emma Russell, right?
Before we go any farther,
I got one question.
Tap or no tap?
No tap.
- Excuse me, what is "tap"?
- Water.
They put fluoride in it.
Learned it from the Nazis.
Theory is it makes you docile,
easy to manipulate.
Oh, I drink tap water.
Yeah, I kind of figured that.
But she does the thinking
for both of you,
so it should be all right.
- Thanks.
- Okay.
What you got?
I believe Godzilla's most recent attacks
haven't just been random.
I think he targeted the Apex facility.
I'm of the same opinion.
But why?
What is Apex up to that's provoking him?
For five years, I embedded
myself inside this company,
trying to figure out
what their game was.
Then, last week...
I saw this.
A manifest of huge cargo
being sent from here
to Apex headquarters in Hong Kong,
which makes no sense because
we are not equipped for heavy shipping.
- Then what?
- And then boom!
Godzilla shows up.
Caved in half the facility,
but I got a sneak peek
at some suspicious tech
which was hidden in a secret bunker.
I mean,
some pretty damn suspicious tech.
Yeah, but what is that?
That's, um...
That's Katzunari single malt whiskey.
Yeah, but it's in a gun holster.
It was a gift from my Sara.
You have a Sara?
She was my wife.
Um, she passed on.
[Bernie sighs]
She was my rock.
My truth.
I'll tell you something,
the day that this goes empty,
that's the day you know I've given up.
[Madison] Bernie.
I think we can help each other.
Okay, I guess now that we're a team,
I feel like we should
come up with a plan.
We're breaking into Apex.
- [Josh] Wait, what?
- [Bernie] You heard her.
Tap water.
Shit.
[groans]
[grunts contentedly]
[Ilene] Hey.
[in sign language]
Thank you.
How is she?
Calm. So calm, it's scary. [chuckles]
That was extraordinary.
I have been signing the alphabet.
Basic commands.
I thought that he showed recognition,
but he never...
Do you have any idea how long
they've been communicating?
No.
I knew that they had a bond.
He trusts her.
Without her,
he'd be tearing the ship apart.
You know, Jia's parents
were killed on the island.
When the storm took over the island,
it wiped out the native people.
But Kong saved her.
She had nowhere to go.
So I made a promise,
then and there, to protect her.
And I think that in some way,
he did the same.
Do you think he would take
directions from her?
No.
If we have someone
who can keep the reins on Kong...
Yeah, no one can keep the reins on Kong.
And she's a child.
[distant, muffled pulsing]
[muffled groaning]
[Nathan] I know Jia is only a child.
But she's the only one
he'll communicate with.
And we need Kong
to find that power source.
The world needs him.
[alarm blaring]
[muffled moaning]
[indistinct shouting]
What's she saying?
Godzilla.
[roaring]
[urgent chatter]
- [Kong grunts]
- [metal clangs]
Did we change course?
No. We're nowhere
near the areas you flagged.
It looks like he's coming for us anyway.
[Ilene] He's not coming for us.
Him? Then dump him. Dump the monkey!
How about we throw you off instead, huh?
[roars]
We have to release him.
If we lose Kong, the mission is over.
He's a sitting duck out there.
We have to let him protect himself.
And us.
[weapons firing]
[roars]
[roaring]
[groans]
Delta...
[screams]
[roaring]
[high-pitched roar]
[roars]
[men scream]
[people screaming]
[growls]
[Godzilla groans]
[Ilene] Oh, my God, Jia!
Nathan?
[roars]
[yelling]
[both snarling]
[alarm beeping]
[growling]
[roaring]
[moans]
[roars]
[roaring]
[Godzilla screeching]
[screeches]
[Kong moans]
[electrical throbbing]
[Godzilla screeches]
He needs our help.
There must be some way
to disorient Godzilla.
Depth charges.
[buzzer sounding]
[snarling]
[growls, yells]
[muffled explosion]
[man] Run!
[retches]
[coughing]
[Nathan] He's circling back.
This won't end
until one of them submits.
[groaning softly]
- [Nathan] Shut it down.
- What?
All of it.
Guns, engines.
- Shut it down. Right now.
- If we do that, we're dead.
No, we're playing dead.
And we're making him think
that he's won.
[mic whines]
Cut the power. Cut the engines.
Kill anything that makes a noise.
[power shutting down]
[silence descends]
This better work.
[in sign language]
[moans weakly]
[Ilene] As soon as we move,
he'll be back.
How are we supposed
to get the rest of the way?
How's Kong with heights?
So, what's the plan?
[Bernie] We find out
what's on Sublevel 33.
- [bottle clinks]
- [Josh] Ow.
Keep it moving, tap water.
Go ahead.
[panting]
All right, Mad Hatter.
Down the rabbit hole.
Okay. We got this.
Oh, my God!
[Josh] Are you sure
we can trust this guy?
Yeah, why?
Well, mainly because he says
crazy shit all the time
and carries a bottle of whiskey
from his dead wife like a gun.
I think it's romantic.
Whoo-hoo!
I really don't understand women.
[grunts]
Okay, come on.
- [electricity crackling]
- [gasps]
[Bernie] This whole thing came down,
and there was this...
eye.
[Josh] Uh, what are we looking at?
[Bernie] No, no, no, no.
No, it was here.
I swear to God, it was...
it was right there.
Hey, guys.
- [button beeps]
- [door buzzes]
Anyone know where this leads to?
You believe me, right?
'Cause I know that
there was something here.
[Josh] I'm gonna get a migraine
from that torch.
"Sublevel."
How deep does this thing go, Bernie?
Hell. Goes to hell.
[female automated voice] Sublevel 33.
[male automated voice]
Maglev shuttle departure
to Roswell, New Mexico at 0900 hours.
[mechanical whine]
[Josh] Whoa. [chuckles]
[indistinct PA announcement]
What is all this?
It's breakaway civilization.
I mean, come on. This is page one
in the Apex-playing-God handbook. Huh?
I mean, the Illuminati
running shadow economies
all to fund a hidden colony
for the elite
in case any of these governments
and megacorporations
accidentally hit the doomsday button.
- It makes sense if you think about it.
- Yeah, sure.
[indistinct shouting]
- [Madison] Someone's coming.
- What?
- Someone's coming.
- [Josh] Someone's coming?
- [Madison] Yes!
Oh, my God.
[muffled squelching]
- [Josh] They look like eggs.
- Skull-crawlers.
What's Apex doing with skull-crawlers?
[man] All right, let's load it up!
- [screams]
- [alarm blares]
[Bernie] What was that?
What was that?
- [engine humming]
- No way. No, no, no. Come on.
Okay, guys, I think we're moving.
It says we're headed
to Apex headquarters in Hong Kong.
- What?
- [Bernie] Hong Kong.
That means that
we're gonna get some answers.
[automated voice] G10, clear for launch.
[engine thrumming]
[engine accelerating]
Here we go.
[muffled pulsing]
We're getting close!
- [indistinct radio chatter]
- [alarm blaring]
[harnesses snapping]
[grunts softly]
[moans]
[grunting curiously]
[wind whistling]
[Kong grunting softly]
[in sign language]
[moans]
[snuffles]
[grunts softly]
[snorts]
It's not working.
Just wait. Wait, wait, wait.
What if she tells him
there are others down there like him?
But you don't know that.
We lost our entire fleet getting here.
There's no way back for him.
And he can't survive here.
[growls softly]
[moaning]
All right. All right.
[softly] Hey.
[in sign language]
[sighs]
[grunts softly]
[snarls]
He's going. Prepare to launch!
Everybody to their station.
We gotta go.
[man on PA] All flights crews cleared
for immediate HEAV launch.
[pilot 1 ] HEAV 1 online.
We're clear for launch.
[control] Copy that, HEAV 1.
[pilot 2] HEAV 2 online.
Exiting hangar now.
[control] HEAV 2, confirmation 4055.
[pilot 3] This is HEAV 3 online,
launching now.
We'll follow him from behind.
There.
There he is.
[indistinct radio chatter]
[engine revving]
[growls]
Are you sure the monkey's
gonna survive this?
Oh, he'll be fine.
It's us I'd worry about.
We're about to be launched
1,000 miles in two seconds
until gravity inverts itself
and spits us into free fall.
It'll be the most amazing thing
you've ever seen.
[rumbling]
Here. For the vomit.
What?
[growls]
[Kong groans]
[Maia yelps, panting]
[alarm blaring]
[Kong roaring]
[silence descends]
[grunting]
[distorted screaming]
[automated voice]
Engine failure, gravity low.
- Engine failure.
- [alarm blaring]
[Kong growls]
[alarms blaring]
[screaming]
[Kong groans]
[roars]
All Delta, reverse gravity propulsion!
[screams]
[creatures screeching]
[Maia panting]
[creature squawking]
[creatures chittering]
It's beautiful.
[pilot on radio] This is HEAV 3,
we're getting some
strange radar activity.
We're gonna circle back and...
[gasps]
[creature screeching]
[all screaming]
[Kong growling]
[creature screeching]
[Kong roars]
[roars]
[snarling]
[Kong roars]
All Delta, prepare to attack!
[creature screeching]
[thudding]
[Kong grunting]
[bones crunching]
[creature screeching]
[panting]
[roars]
[grunting]
That's gross.
[Ilene on radio] Kong's on the move.
We gotta go.
[creatures chittering]
[growling]
[Nathan on radio]
Well, he seems to know where he's going.
Oh, he certainly can move.
[thud echoes]
[rocks thudding]
[whines]
[mellow instrumental music playing]
[grunts softly]
[whooshes]
[rumbling]
Okay, okay.
Creepy monorail is slowing down.
[announcer on PA] Attention:
Shipping pod arriving.
[announcer repeating in Cantonese]
[rapid beeping]
[horn blares]
[automated voice speaking indistinctly]
[Bernie] Okay. Keep quiet. Follow me.
[gate thuds]
We're going in?
Yeah.
Oh, no!
Every time, I swear. Doors hate us.
[Bernie] Oh, yeah.
- [Bernie] Aah!
- [Madison] Oh, my God!
It's just so massive. It's so stupid.
So, what is this place?
Well, if there's
a corporate-friendly term
for "sacrifice pit,"
I'd say we are in it.
[Madison] Oh, God, that stinks.
[alarm blaring]
That's not good. Bernie!
[Bernie] I really hate this place.
[automated voice]
Attention: Demonstration
in T-minus one minute.
All personnel
are to stay clear of the area.
[machines powering up]
[engineer] Mr. Simmons,
systems are coming online now.
[exhales]
[metal clanking]
Commence uplink.
[keyboard clacking]
[Ren] Engaging uplink.
[automated voice] Pilot engaged.
[whirring]
[pulsing]
[roars]
[Bernie mumbling]
That's robot Godzilla.
Oh, no. That's...
That's Mechagodzilla.
[metal thudding]
[metal clanking]
[Walter] Release number 10.
[gate thuds]
[snarling]
[both screaming]
[Bernie] Go, go! Go through there!
Madison!
[roars]
[both screaming]
[Bernie] Madison! Run, girl!
Run, girl. Go!
- [skull-crawler roars]
- [Madison shrieks]
[gasps]
[screeching]
[chuckles softly]
[Bernie] Yes!
[system powers down]
- [squelching]
- [Bernie exclaims]
Damn it. [sighs]
[Ren over comms]
System only reached 40% power.
[Walter] Oh, I know.
As expected.
Don't worry. Once the Hollow Earth
sample is uploaded,
our power troubles will be over.
[Ren] If they can find the source.
[Walter] Oh, they'll find it.
I have faith in my daughter.
I have faith in our creation.
And humanity will once again...
be the apex species.
This is why Godzilla attacked
the Apex facility.
[scoffs] They're trying to replace him.
[Mechagodzilla warbling]
[growls]
[Mark] Come on, Maddie.
[signal beeping]
[tech on radio] Sir, Godzilla just made
an abrupt change in direction.
He's moving very fast.
Projections show
he's likely headed to Hong Kong.
Transport is ready
and waiting to take you there, sir.
[thunder cracks]
[mouthing]
[Nathan] That has to be it.
[thunder cracks, rumbles]
[grunts softly]
[growls inquisitively]
[straining]
[energy pulsating]
[roars]
[roar echoes]
We were right.
He's home.
[automated voice]
All personnel must display
their Apex employee badge at all times.
[whispering] Follow me.
Lizard people build all their facilities
the same way. I can find the exit.
[Josh gasps]
[Bernie] The exit's this way.
Guys. Madison!
Oh, my God.
[Bernie] Bitch, what?
[Josh] It's a Titan skull.
[Bernie] No, no, no.
That's not just any Titan.
That's Monster Zero.
[gasps] Ghidorah.
[Bernie] They hardwired its DNA.
Self-generating neural pathways
capable of intuitive learning.
[Josh] Okay, I'm smart,
but I only go to high school.
- It's a living supercomputer.
- [Josh] Shh.
[gasps in disbelief]
[Bernie] It had three heads.
Its necks were so long,
they communicated telepathically.
And there's one here
and another one inside of that thing.
Yeah, it could be a psionic interface.
[exclaims] Oh, my God.
[whispers] Careful.
[Madison] It's a pilot.
[Bernie] Yeah. He's in a Trance.
That's a psionic uplink.
It follows his will.
Oh, Apex, what have you done?
[people clamoring and screaming]
[roars]
- [car alarms blaring]
- [horn blaring]
[stomping]
[people screaming]
[growling]
This is the day we feared.
I've given the order, Doctor.
- [people screaming]
- The city is being evacuated.
[screaming continues]
[Maia] I don't understand.
He led us here. Where is it?
[energy pulsates]
[grunts]
[Maia] What is he doing?
[energy surging]
[Ilene] It's the axe.
It's drawing radiation from the core
like it's charging.
[roars]
[energy charging up]
[Walter] Whoa! Godzilla's responding!
They found it!
[siren blaring]
[Mark] What in the hell?
[robot chittering]
What are you doing?
[Maia] Extracting a sample.
[Ilene] This is a power
beyond our understanding.
You can't just drill into it.
[Maia] Actually, we can.
My father gets what he wants.
That's Apex property now.
[Ilene] What?
[system beeping]
Energy signature incoming.
We should be able to recreate it soon.
That is the discovery of the millennium.
- You can't strip it for parts.
- Hold it.
[guns cocking]
[roars]
[rumbling]
[creatures screeching]
[Kong growls]
Go. Go. Got what we needed.
Let's go!
[beeping]
Yes.
Mr. Serizawa, start your engines!
The upgrade is untested.
Once we get online,
Gojira will come straight for us.
He's been coming for us
since our creation first awoke.
- We must embrace it.
- We shouldn't rush this.
We have no idea how this energy source
will affect the Mecha.
Get in the goddamn chair.
[Apex guard screaming]
[Kong growling]
[gunfire]
[Apex guard 2 screaming]
- [Maia] Go, go, go!
- [pilot] Come on, come on!
Move! What are you waiting for?
Let's go!
[pilot] This way, sir! Hurry!
We gotta get back...
- [pilot screams]
- [Ilene exclaims]
[pilot grunts, screams]
[creature 2 screeches]
[creatures snarling]
[hissing and snarling]
[squawking]
[Ilene gasps]
[screeching]
Okay.
- [grunts]
- [screeches]
[screeching]
[thuds]
[Kong grunts]
[roars]
[Kong roars]
Get him out of the way! Shoot him!
- Go, go, go!
- [roars]
[thuds]
[roars]
- [alarm blaring]
- [Kong growls]
Oh, no.
No, no, no...
[Nathan] Oh, Jesus!
Come on, let's go!
[thuds]
[growls]
[growls angrily]
[beeping]
- Hold on, ladies.
- Yeah.
[Nathan] Whoa.
[exhales nervously]
[beeping]
Stay low.
[camera clicking]
[gasps]
[softly] Yeah. Going viral.
What?
We've gotta try and stop this.
[metal creaking and thudding
in distance]
I don't like this, guys.
If this wasn't contributing
to world destruction,
this would be a great DJ booth.
I know what it... Maintenance.
- [Bernie mumbling]
- Madison, we should go.
[Bernie] I'm Maintenance.
You don't have to alert the...
She doesn't buy that.
Uh, Madison, we need to go.
The woman with the villain hairdo,
- she's getting security.
- Madison, they have guns.
Hey, guys. Uh, it's soundproof
so I can't really...
- I wanna communicate...
- Open the door!
Say again?
Oh, God! Get down! Get down!
[Madison] Oh, shit! [gasps]
[chuckles nervously]
[car alarm blares]
[people screaming]
[Kong growling]
[roars]
[growls]
[both roaring]
[people screaming]
- [Godzilla screeches]
- [Kong groans]
[energy charging up]
[Kong grunts]
[roars]
[energy charging up]
[Kong growling]
[sirens wailing]
[yelping]
[roars]
[growls]
We're about to breach the veil! Hold on!
[Kong roaring]
[both screaming]
- [grunting heavily]
- [exclaims]
[Kong roars]
[roars]
[explosion]
[grunting]
Looks like round two goes to Kong.
[Ilene breathing heavily]
Hey!
Oh, come on, guys.
Really? Greenpeace again?
[laughs] Greenpea...
Actually, sir,
not like you would know this,
but I'm Level Two
Assistant Engineering...
Well, Provisional Level Two
Assistant Engineering,
not like you would know that.
My evaluations
were incredibly encourag...
I'm just saying Greenpeace wishes,
is all I'm saying.
Where do I know you from?
Oh, my goodness.
Director Russell's daughter, yes?
You caused all of this.
If by "all of this,"
you mean I, and I alone,
have given humanity a chance
against the Titans,
then, yes, I will own that title.
Godzilla had left us in peace.
You provoked him into war.
There can only be one alpha,
Miss Russell.
It seems to have been providence.
[chuckles]
[Godzilla growling]
[Godzilla roars]
[Kong roars]
[Kong groans]
[both growling]
[groans]
[Godzilla roars]
[Kong groans]
[Kong groaning]
[groans]
[Godzilla roars]
[Kong groaning]
[growls]
[Godzilla roars]
[roars]
[groans]
[whimpers]
[growls weakly]
[pensive music playing]
[Walter over comms] It's time to launch.
Begin pilot integration.
And now...
my Mecha.
It's not only Godzilla's equal...
but his superior.
[Mechagodzilla powering up]
The Apex Titan of my own hand.
[laughs]
[over comms] It's time to show
the world what you can do.
[automated voice] Pilot engaged.
Alert: Failure. System unstable.
[distorted] Alert: Failure.
System unstable.
This is how we, as a species, win.
You see, ten years ago,
when Gojira was first revealed
to the world,
I had a dream.
And in that dream, I saw one thing.
And that beautiful, amazing thing was...
Oh, shit.
No!
[electricity crackling]
[grunting]
[all coughing]
It's unfair. [coughs]
I really wanted to hear
the rest of that speech.
[loud thudding]
[Mechagodzilla roars]
[car alarms blaring]
What in God's name is that?
[warbling]
[roars]
[groans]
[people clamoring and screaming]
[metal clanking]
[groaning]
It's thinking for itself now.
We have to warn Monarch.
Or try to stop it ourselves.
That thing's still linked
to their satellite.
[Bernie] Wait, Josh.
[Josh] If I can figure out the password,
maybe we can shut it down.
All right.
[Nathan grunts]
[Ilene gasps]
What the hell is that?
[Godzilla roars]
[silence descends]
[muffled heartbeat]
- What?
- [in sign language]
What's happening?
She can feel his heartbeat.
He's dying.
[Kong groaning softly]
There's nothing we can do
to restart his heart.
We'd need a charge big enough to...
Light up Las Vegas for a week.
[roars]
- [Bernie] Is that a password?
- [system buzzing]
[shouts] Is that a password?
I don't know! I'm not used to this.
I'm used to pirating movies online.
- Okay, then go to Settings.
- [line ringing]
- [on phone] This is Mark.
- Dad?
Madison, where are you?
Dad, can you hear...
Can you hear me? I'm in Hong Kong.
- Mad?
- Dad!
Mad? Madison!
[alarm blaring]
- [engine powers up]
- A-ha!
[chuckles]
Okay, you two better get some distance.
Hey.
You are a very brave little girl.
[in sign language]
I don't know.
Maybe we both are.
- [roars]
- [energy charging up]
[warbling]
[roars]
Okay.
Good luck, big fella.
[system alarm beeping]
[beeping intensifies]
- [explosion]
- [Kong gasps]
[growls]
[panting]
[in sign language]
[roars]
[growls]
[groans]
[roars]
- [bones cracking]
- [growls]
I thought you said you were a hacker!
I said I took an HTML course
at summer camp.
- HTML?
- Yes, at summer camp.
Was it a '90s camp?
Come on. Use QWERTY.
[automated voice] Error. Security lock.
- [alarm blaring]
- [Josh] No. Shit!
Shit.
[breathing heavily]
[Godzilla whimpering]
[Kong roars]
[Godzilla roars]
- [whirring]
- [roars]
[Madison] Josh!
You have to do something.
We tried to take down
those Apex bastards,
but I think this is as far as we go,
so bottom's up.
I was hoping to die with adults,
but okay.
[Bernie] If you've never
had a drink before,
now's the time 'cause...
Drink. Drink!
- [Bernie] Hey! What are you...
- [static]
That's your solution?
I gotta die here with you, and sober!
[explosion]
[whirring stops]
[electricity crackling]
[Kong growls]
[energy surging]
[grunts]
[Kong roars]
- [Bernie] Yeah!
- [Josh] Yes! Yes!
[metal clangs]
[growls]
[roars]
[electricity crackling]
[groaning]
[echoes] Hey, Nathan?
[soft instrumental music plays]
- Nathan?
- [gasps softly]
Nathan, are you okay?
[helicopters hovering]
[crowd chattering]
[sirens wailing]
Dad?
Dad!
- Dad!
- I love you.
[Mark gasps]
[crying]
Hi. Um, it was, um... Madison's idea.
Shut up, Josh.
Dad. This is the man
who saved our lives.
Bernie, meet Dad.
Dad. Uh, Bernie.
Um, it's an absolute pleasure
to meet you.
[hesitates] I was wondering
if I could invite you onto my podcast
to talk about the Monarch facility
in Roswell because...
[Bernie continues indistinctly]
It's amazing. It happened...
- [Godzilla roars]
- [Bernie screams]
[Kong grunting]
Jia? Jia!
[roars]
[Godzilla roars]
["The Air That I Breathe" playing]
[indistinct chatter]
Heads up, guys! He's coming
around for his morning walk.
[men shouting]
[in sign language]
Sometimes
[grunting]
All I need is the air that I breathe
[roar echoes]
And to love you
All I need is the air that I breathe
Yes, to love you
Sometimes
All I need is the air that I breathe
And to love you
Yes, to love you